<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SFOSC – About SFOSC</title>
    <link>https://sfosc.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About SFOSC on SFOSC</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://sfosc.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About: Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://sfosc.org/about/code_of_conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfosc.org/about/code_of_conduct/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page details guidelines for interaction and behavior in the SFOSC community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;contributor-covenant-code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-pledge&#34;&gt;Our Pledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as
contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and
our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body
size, disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression,
level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal
appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-standards&#34;&gt;Our Standards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment
include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using welcoming and inclusive language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gracefully accepting constructive criticism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing on what is best for the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing empathy towards other community members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of unacceptable behavior by participants include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of sexualized language or imagery and unwelcome sexual attention or
advances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trolling, insulting/derogatory comments, and personal or political attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public or private harassment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing others&amp;rsquo; private information, such as a physical or electronic
address, without explicit permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other conduct which could reasonably be considered inappropriate in a
professional setting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Our Responsibilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers are responsible for clarifying the standards of acceptable
behavior and are expected to take appropriate and fair corrective action in
response to any instances of unacceptable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers have the right and responsibility to remove, edit, or
reject comments, commits, code, wiki edits, issues, and other contributions
that are not aligned to this Code of Conduct, or to ban temporarily or
permanently any contributor for other behaviors that they deem inappropriate,
threatening, offensive, or harmful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scope&#34;&gt;Scope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct applies both within project spaces and in public spaces
when an individual is representing the project or its community. Examples of
representing a project or community include using an official project e-mail
address, posting via an official social media account, or acting as an appointed
representative at an online or offline event. Representation of a project may be
further defined and clarified by project maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enforcement&#34;&gt;Enforcement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instances of abusive, harassing, or otherwise unacceptable behavior may be
reported by contacting the project team at adam@stalecoffee.org. All
complaints will be reviewed and investigated and will result in a response that
is deemed necessary and appropriate to the circumstances. The project team is
obligated to maintain confidentiality with regard to the reporter of an incident.
Further details of specific enforcement policies may be posted separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project maintainers who do not follow or enforce the Code of Conduct in good
faith may face temporary or permanent repercussions as determined by other
members of the project&amp;rsquo;s leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Code of Conduct is adapted from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant&lt;/a&gt;, version 1.4,
available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/version/1/4/code-of-conduct.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For answers to common questions about this code of conduct, see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/faq&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/faq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About: Contributing</title>
      <link>https://sfosc.org/about/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfosc.org/about/contributing/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page includes information about contributing to SFOSC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;request-for-contributions&#34;&gt;Request for Contributions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to have you help us evolve the principles, write new social
contracts, and further explore what it means to create sustainable free and
open source communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, we seek the following types of contributions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ideas: participate in an issues thread or start your own to voice your idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;copy editing: contribute your expertise by helping us expand, clarify and proofing our content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code: improve the design, usability and functionality of the sfosc page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;artwork: contribute graphics or any other artwork improving the presentation of sfosc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this guide on how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-contribute-ideas&#34;&gt;How to contribute ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-contribute-code&#34;&gt;How to contribute code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-to-conduct-yourself-when-contributing&#34;&gt;How to conduct yourself when contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-contribute-ideas&#34;&gt;How to Contribute Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: familiarity with &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/features/issues/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our community mainly communicates over github issues threads. Please voice any idea,
criticism or feedback in them so we can have an open discussion. Of course you can
also feel free to contact any of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/MEMBERSHIP.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;members&lt;/a&gt;
privately if you think this is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-contribute-code&#34;&gt;How to Contribute Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;: familiarity with &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/using-pull-requests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Pull Requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to contribute code, fork the repository and make a pull-request
with your changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to view/test your changes locally before, you can build this static
web page with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;, please check their extensive documentation
on how to install and use this site generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/MEMBERSHIP.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sfosc member&lt;/a&gt;
will review your pull-request. And if the pull request gets a positive review
the reviewer will merge it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, please bear in mind the following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discuss-large-changes-in-advance&#34;&gt;Discuss Large Changes in Advance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you see a glaring flaw within the SFOSC, resist the urge to jump into the
code and make sweeping changes right away. We know it can be tempting, but
especially for large, structural changes it&amp;rsquo;s a wiser choice to first discuss
them in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue list&lt;/a&gt;.
It may turn out that someone is already working on this or that someone already
has tried to solve this and hit a roadblock, maybe there even is a good reason
why that flaw exists. If nothing else, a discussion of the change will usually
familiarize the reviewer with your proposed changes and streamline the review
process when you finally create a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good rule of thumb for when you should discuss on the issue list is to
estimate how much time would be wasted if the pull request was rejected. If
it&amp;rsquo;s a couple of minutes then you can probably dive head first and eat the loss
in the worst case. Otherwise, making a quick check with the other developers
could save you lots of time down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;small-commits-pull-request-scope&#34;&gt;Small Commits &amp;amp; Pull Request Scope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A commit should contain a single logical change, the scope should be as small
as possible. And a pull request should only consist of the commits that you
need for your change. If it&amp;rsquo;s possible for you to split larger changes into
smaller blocks please do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting the scope of commits/pull requests makes reviewing much easier.
Because it will usually mean each commit can be evaluated independently and a
smaller amount of commits per pull request usually also means a smaller amount
of code to be reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;proper-commit-messages&#34;&gt;Proper Commit Messages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are keen on proper commit messages because they will help us to maintain
this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The title of your commit should summarizes &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; has been done

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the title is to small to explain &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; you have done then elaborate on it in the body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; you have changed this instead of the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. This is the most important content of the message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain potential side-effects of this change, if there are any&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please also:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leave a blank line between the commit subject and body&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools like rebase could not work properly otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mention related issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this commit fixes an issue you need to mention it like &lt;code&gt;Fixes #1234&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give kudos to Co-authors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the commit has more than one author tag them with &lt;code&gt;Co-authored-by: name &amp;lt;name@example.com&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try that the commit subject is not longer than 50 characters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try that each line of the commit body is not longer than 72 characters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-conduct-yourself&#34;&gt;How to Conduct Yourself&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please make sure that while contributing you follow our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Hacking! - :heart: Your SFOSC Team&lt;/p&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About: Membership</title>
      <link>https://sfosc.org/about/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfosc.org/about/membership/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page includes information about membership in SFOSC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;membership-in-the-sfosc&#34;&gt;Membership in the SFOSC&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome! Anyone who is interested in contributing to the SFOSC in any way is welcome
to become a member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membership is &lt;strong&gt;not a requirement&lt;/strong&gt; for participating in the community.
Members may be consulted about governance of the community. For example through votes.
The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING GUIDELINES&lt;/a&gt;
explain several ways you can contribute regardless of membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membership in the community is broad based, available to anyone who is
participating in any fashion. Requirements for membership involve a minimal
amount of verification of identity, and proof of engagement with the community.
Membership consists solely of individuals - there are no corporate community
members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the only privilege membership brings is being able
to vote for the project leader. And, of course, the glory of having your name appended
to this file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;applying&#34;&gt;Applying&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To apply for membership, send a pull request to this file, adding your name and
GitHub username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please mention why you became interested in SFOSC and share some related work.
This is optional though, please share only as much as you would like to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing members will review your application.
The aspects we look for currently are:
- Full name and GitHub username, to serve as minimal verification of identity.
- You have either engaged with SFOSC directly, or have related experience we can verify.
  If this experience is not easily found from your GitHub profile, please mention it
  as part of the pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested, but not sure if you meet the requirements?
Go ahead and submit your pull request! We&amp;rsquo;re glad you&amp;rsquo;re interested and there to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;members&#34;&gt;Members&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adam Jacob (adamhjk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karl Amrhein (karlamrhein)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elias Secchi (eliassecchi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camille Moulin (camillem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel Thompson-Yvetot (nothingismagick)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanessa Sochat (vsoch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Alfano (themightychris)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nick Kellett (nickkellett)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marc Laporte (marclaporte)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robin van Boven (beanow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pradyun Gedam (pradyunsg)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ranjib Dey (ranjib)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About: Social Contract</title>
      <link>https://sfosc.org/about/social_contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfosc.org/about/social_contract/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page includes information about SFOSC social contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document describe the social contract for the community around a piece of
open source software (&amp;ldquo;the software&amp;rdquo;). It lays out the moral and ethical rules
the community agrees to in order to ensure a long, healthy, sustainable life
for the software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not a legal agreement, although sections of it reference legal
agreements. It is a moral and ethical one - it is the foundation upon which the
community is built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By joining the community, you agree to the rules and beliefs outlined in this
social contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;principles&#34;&gt;Principles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sfosc.github.io/principles&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;We follow the principles of sustainable free and open source
communities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are a unified body of individuals, scattered throughout the larger society,
who work in support of the creation, evolution, use, and extension of the
software; while ensuring its longevity through meeting the needs of the present
without compromising the ability of the community of the future to meet its own
needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want the software to exist, to solve our problems, to continue to improve,
and to be available for our use. Therefore, we commit that we will uphold
these four freedoms for all, under all circumstances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The freedom to run the program as you wish, for any purpose (freedom 0).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The freedom to study how the program works, and change it so it does your computing as you wish (freedom 1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help others (freedom 2).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The freedom to distribute copies of your modified versions to others (freedom 3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do this because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We believe that software is better when it is produced in the commons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We believe that sustainable communities are based on just and fair institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We value the ability of every person to use the software to better their
own lives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;governance&#34;&gt;Governance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure that all people are welcome, treated fairly and safely, this
community has a code of conduct, published at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CODE OF CONDUCT&lt;/a&gt;. It applies equally to
all members of the community, both on-line and in person. Membership and participation
in the community requires following the Code of Conduct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;membership&#34;&gt;Membership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membership is &lt;strong&gt;not a requirement&lt;/strong&gt; for participating in the community.
Members may be consulted about governance of the community. For example through votes.
The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING GUIDELINES&lt;/a&gt;
explain several ways you can contribute regardless of membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Membership in the community is broad based, available to anyone who is
participating in any fashion. Requirements for membership involve a minimal
amount of verification of identity, and proof of engagement with the community.
Membership consists solely of individuals - there are no corporate community
members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guidelines for membership can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/MEMBERSHIP.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MEMBERSHIP GUIDELINES&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;voting&#34;&gt;Voting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Periodically, the membership may be requested to vote in elections, or on a referendum
on an important issue. Each member is entitled to a single vote, and all votes count
equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guidelines for voting can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/VOTING.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;VOTING GUIDELINES&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;leadership&#34;&gt;Leadership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership in the community is based on a strong executive model. The Project
Leader will be elected by a simple majority vote according to the voting
guidelines. The Project Leader will serve for 1 year, at the end of which a new
election for Project Leader will be held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Project Leader has broad authority to manage the project as they see fit, to
delegate positions of authority, and to enact new governance rules. The
exception is amending this social contract. This can only be done with a &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;
vote of the membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new election can be held for the Project Leader at any time, regardless of
term, based on a simple majority vote of the membership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full set of guidelines for the Project can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/RULES.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PROJECT RULES&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;licensing-copyrights-patents-and-trademarks&#34;&gt;Licensing, Copyrights, Patents, and Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;software-license&#34;&gt;Software License&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All software produced by the community will be published under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOFTWARE
LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;. All contributors to the software agree to publish their work under
this license, and to have it included in any distributions or derivatives
allowed under the same terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;copyrights&#34;&gt;Copyrights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All copyrights remain the property of the original copyright holder, under the
terms of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOFTWARE LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;patents&#34;&gt;Patents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any patents included in the software must be made available under the same
terms as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOFTWARE LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trademarks&#34;&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any trademarks that may exist, relating to the software directly, are the
ethical property of the community itself. Their use in the software is made
available under the same terms as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SOFTWARE LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further details can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/TRADEMARK.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TRADEMARK POLICY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;economic-sustainability&#34;&gt;Economic Sustainability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-intent&#34;&gt;Community Intent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any commercial activity around the software should, in part, further the
sustainability of the community. The potential for economic benefit is
available to all members of the community equally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;donations&#34;&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will be sustained through a donation model. Currently the
project has no expenses, so no system of donations is yet available.&lt;/p&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About: Trademark</title>
      <link>https://sfosc.org/about/trademark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfosc.org/about/trademark/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page includes information about SFOSC trademarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;trademark-policy&#34;&gt;Trademark Policy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sustainable Free and Open Source Community, and the SFOSC, are not currently
trademarked. We do ask that, if you want to republish this content, you do so in
line with the terms of our license.

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About: Voting</title>
      <link>https://sfosc.org/about/voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 12:27:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sfosc.org/about/voting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        

&lt;div class=&#34;pageinfo pageinfo-primary&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page details guidelines for voting in SFOSC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;voting-guidelines&#34;&gt;Voting Guidelines&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every member in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sfosc/sfosc/blob/master/MEMBERSHIP.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MEMBERSHIP&lt;/a&gt; file is
allowed one vote. We will use &lt;a href=&#34;https://heliosvoting.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Helios&lt;/a&gt; to organize the
actual vote, and certify the results.

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
